[{"question": "What is the minimum value that can be given to become betrothed?", 
"answer": "A woman may be acquired by giving a perutah, which is the value of one half grain of barley's weight in silver, or anything of equivalent value.", 
"source": "Kiddushin 1:1"},
{"question": "If a woman who is an ervah to a man falls to him for yibum, can her rival wives peform yibum?",
"answer": "No, the rival wives of an ervah are prohibited from yibum and thus do not need chalitzah to remarry.", 
"source":"Kiddushin 1:4"},
{"question": "If the rival wife of an ervah performs chalitzah, is she fit to marry a kohen upon the death of her husband?",
"answer": "Yes, the rival wife of an ervah who performs chalitzah is not considered to have done anything of consequence through a chalitzah, since she was prohibited from the man in the fist place. Thus, she remains fit to marry a kohen.",
"source": "Kiddushin 1:4"},

{"question": "Are the co-wives of an ervah who falls to a man for yibum permitted to perform yibum?", 
"answer": "No, co-wives to an ervah who all fall for Yibum are prohibited to that man forever.  They do not need to perform chalitzah if he is the only living brother.",
"source":"Yevamot 1:4"},
{"question":"If a woman has done maamar with her yevam, and her sister falls to him for yibum, what is the status of the woman?",
"answer": "The woman must be given a get and her yevam performs chalitzah. He is also obligated to perform chalitzah with the sister. He cannot perform yibumw with her, either.",
"source": "Yevamot 3:5"},

{"question":"If a woman awaiting yibum inherits propery, does she have rights to sell or give it away?",
"answer": "Yes, a woman awaiting yibum has the right to sell or give away her inherited property.",
"source": "Yevamot 4:3"},

{"question":"A woman waiting for yibum dies after a brother performed maamar. Who inherits her property?",
"answer":"Maamar gives the yavam no property rights.  Tson barzel property remains in its previous state.  The ketubah payment is given to the deceased husband's heirs. The melog property is given to the Yevamah's father or his heirs.",
"source":"Yevamot 4:3"},

{"question":"When has a man accomplished the mitzvah of being fruitful and multiplying?",
"answer":"He must father a boy and a girl.",
"source": "Yevamot 6:6"},

{"question": "In which case may a minor gil perform miun to annul her marriage?",
"answer": "At any point in the marriage, a girl who was married off by he mother or brothers as a minor can annul the marriage",
"source": "Yevamot 13:1"},
{"question": "Can a minor girl annul her marriage in front of her deceased husband's brother to whom she fell for levirate marriage?",
"answer": "Yes, the minor girl can annul her marriage in front of her yavam or in front of her living husband.",
"source": "Yevamot 13:1"},
{"question": "Must the refusal of miun be done in the present of her husband?",
"answer": "No, the miun can be done either in the presence of her husband or in his absence.",
"source": "Yevamot 13:1"},
{"question": "Where can the refusal of miun be done?",
"answer": "It can take place in a court or not in a court.",
"source": "Yevamot 13:1"},
{"question": "How many times can a minor peform the miun refusal?",
"answer": "She can refuse as long as she is a minor, even if it takes four or five times.",
"source": "Yevamot 13:1"},
{"question": "Can a woman remarry or perform yibum if she is the only witness claiming that her husband died overseas?",
"answer": "Originally, Beit Hillel ruled that only in cases where the wife claimed the husband died nearby was she beileved.  However, Beit Shammai convinced them that she could be believed even if the husband was abroad. ",
"source": "Yevamot 15:2"},
{"question": "Can a woman recieve her ketubah payment if she is the only witness claiming that her husband died overseas?",
"answer": "Originally, Beit Hilled ruled that while she could remarry, she could not receive her ketubah payment, because the Torah states that matters of finances require two valid witnesses in Deuteronomy 19:15.  However, Beit Shammai convinced them that she could receive her ketubah payment, because it is contingent on her permission to remarry.",
"source": "Yevamot 15:3"}

]